So, I'm going to take us back to 2007.
سأعود بكم إلى العام 2007.
I'd just spent about six months working on album
حيث قضيت حوالي ستة أشهر وأنا أعمل على البوم
that I'd poured my heart and my soul into,
بكل تفان وإخلاص،
and it was getting about three plays per day on Myspace at the time,
وكان هناك ثلاث مشاهدات فقط في اليوم علي موقع "ماي سبيس" في ذلك الوقت،
and I was getting more and more depressed when I started noticing these other people
كنت اُحبط أكثر فأكثر عندما بدأت بملاحظة الأشخاص الآخرين
who were playing guitar and singing
الذين يعزفون الجيتار ويغنون
and putting videos on this new site called YouTube,
ويضعون الفيديوهات على هذا الموقع المسمى "يوتيوب،"
and they were getting 300,000 views.
حصلوا على 300,000 مشاهدة.
So I decided I'm going to start making some Youtube videos.
لذا قررت أن أبدأ بعمل بعض الفيديوهات على اليوتيوب.
And one day they featured a video of my band on the homepage,
وفي أحد الأيام وضعوا فيديو فرقتي على الصفحة الرئيسية،
which was amazing -- we got a bunch of new fans.
كان ذلك رائعاً... حصلنا على مجموعة من المعجبين.
We also got a bunch of people
وحصلنا أيضا على مجموعة من الناس
who, I guess, just didn't really like the music or something --
الذين، أعتقد، أنهم لم يعجبوا حقا بالموسيقي أو شيء من هذا القبيل...
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's OK because people started coming to our shows,
ولكن هذا جيد لأن الناس بدأوا بالمجيئ إلى عروضنا
and we started touring,
وبدأنا بعمل جولات
and we came out with a record.
وعملنا تسجيلات.
And when I checked our bank account balance
وعندما تفقدت رصيد حسابنا البنكي
after our first monthly iTunes payout,
بعد أول دفعة مالية شهرية من أي تونز
we had 22,000 bucks in it,
وجدنا 22,000 دولاراً في الحساب،
which was amazing because at the time I was living at my dad's house,
كان هذا مذهلاً لأني كنت أعيش في منزل والداي حينئذ،
trying to make a living as a musician by uploading videos to the internet
أحاول كسب عيشي كموسيقيار من خلال رفع الفيديوهات على الإنترنت
which literally zero people respected in 2009 --
وهو أمر لم يعطه الناس أي تقدير في عام 2009
even the people who were uploading videos to the internet.
حتى الأشخاص الذين كانوا يرفعون الفيديوهات على الإنترنت.
And so for the next four years,
وهكذا للسنوات الأربع التالية،
I uploaded more and more videos to the Internet,
رفعت المزيد والمزيد من الفيديوهات على الإنترنت،
and they got better and better,
وصارت أفضل فأفضل،
and we made enough money through brand deals
وحصلنا على مال كاف من خلال صفقات العلامات التجارية
and commercials and iTunes sales
والإعلانات التجارية ومبيعات أي تونز
to buy a house.
لشراء منزل.
And we built a recording studio.
وقمنا بإنشاء أستديو تسجيل.
But there was one big problem:
لكن واجهتنا مشكلة كبيرة:
making money as a creative person in 2013 was super weird.
الحصول على المال كشخص مبدع فى 2013 كان غريباً جداً.
First of all, the business models were changing all the time.
فأسلوب الأعمال التجارية كان يتغير طوال الوقت.
So our 58,000 dollars of annual iTunes download income
لذا دخلنا السنوي البالغ 58,000 دولار من تحميلات أي تونز السنوية
was about to be replaced by about 6,000 dollars of streaming income.
كان على وشك أن يستبدل بحوالي 6,000 دولار من دخل البث.
Steams paid less than downloads.
البث يدفع له أقل من التحميل.
And then as more and more creators started popping up online,
وبعد ذلك بدأ المزيد من المبدعين بالظهور على الإنترنت،
there was just more competition for these five-figure brand deals
كان هناك المزيد من المنافسة على صفقات العلامات التجارية بمئات الآلاف.
that had kept the band afloat for years.
هذا أبقى الفرقة واقفة على قدميها لعدة سنين.
And to top it all off, our videos themselves --
وعلاوة على ذلك ففيديوهاتنا ذاتها...
the creative stuff that we made that our fans loved and appreciated --
الأغاني الخلاقة التي صنعناها جعلت معجبينا يحبونها ويقدرونها...
that were actually contributing value to the world,
لأنها حقا أضافت قيمة لهذا العالم،
those videos were generating almost zero dollars of income for us.
هذه الفيديوهات عائدها لنا تقريباً صفر دولار.
This is an actual snapshot of my YouTube dashboard
هذه لقطة لحسابي على اليوتيوب
from a 28-day period
منذ 28 يوم
that shows one million views
تظهر مليون مشاهدة
and 166 dollars of ad earnings for those views.
و 166 دولار جنيتها من الإعلانات من خلال هذه المشاهدات.
The whole machine in 2013
الآلية بأسرها في 2013
that took art online and outputted money
التي كانت تعرض الفن على الإنترنت لتحوله لمال
was totally nonfunctional.
كانت غير فعالة على الاطلاق.
It doesn't matter if you're a newspaper,
لا يهم إذا كنت تمثل صحيفة،
or an institution,
أو مؤسسة،
or an independent creator.
أو منتج مستقل.
A monthly web comic with 20,000 monthly readers --
فمجلة فكاهية شهرية يقرأها 20,000 شهرياً...
20,000 monthly readers --
20,000 قارئ شهرياً...
gets paid a couple hundred bucks in ad revenue.
يدفع لها بضع مئات الدولارات من عائدات الإعلانات.
This is 20,000 people.
هؤلاء 20,000 شخص.
Like, in what world is this not enough?
في أي عالم هذا يعتبر غير كاف؟
I don't understand.
أنا لا أفهم.
What systems have we built where this is insufficient
أي نظام بنينا حيث يعتبر هذا غير كاف
for a person to make a living?
لأي شخص للحصول على لقمة العيش؟
So, I actually have a theory about this.
لذ، حقيقة أنا لدي نظرية حول هذا.
I think it's been a weird 100 years.
أعتقد أنها كانت 100 سنة غريبة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
About 100 years ago,
قبل حوالي 100 سنة،
humans figured out how to record sound onto a wax cylinder.
عرف البشر كيفية تسجيل الصوت على أسطوانات شمعية.
That was the beginning of the phonograph.
وكان هذا بداية الفونوغراف.
Right around the same time,
وفي نفس الوقت تقريباً،
we figured out how to record light onto a piece of photographic paper,
عرفنا كيف نسجل الصور على قطعة من الورق،
celluloid -- the beginning of film and television.
والشريط السينمائي... وبداية الافلام والتلفاز.
For the first time, you could store art on a thing,
ولأول مرة كنت تستطيع تخزين الفن على شيء.
which was amazing.
كان هذا رائعا.
Art used to be completely ephemeral,
كان الفن سريع الزوال
so if you missed the symphony, you just didn't get to hear the orchestra.
فإذا لم تسمع السمفونية، فلن تستطيع أن تسمع الأوركسترا.
But now, for the first time,
لكن الآن، للمرة الأولى،
you could store the orchestra's performance on a physical object,
أنت تستطيع تخزين الأوركسترا على شيء ملموس،
and like, listen to it later,
وتستمع إليه لاحقا،
which was amazing.
كان رائعاً حقاً.
It was so amazing in fact,
كان رائعاً للغاية،
that for the next 100 years, between 1900 and 2000,
وللمئة سنة التالية، بين 1900 و 2000،
humans built just billions and billions of dollars of infrastructure
صرف البشر المليارات والمليارات على البنية التحتية
to essentially help artists do two things.
لتساعد الفنانين بشكل أساسي على عمل شيئين،
First, put their art on a thing,
أولا، تخزين الفن على شيء،
and second, get that thing around the world
وثانيا، توزيعها على انحاء العالم
to the people who wanted the art.
للناس الذين أرادوا الفن.
So, so much industry is devoted to these two problems.
ولذلك خصصت العديد من الصناعات لتلك المشكلتين.
Oh my gosh, there are trucking companies,
يا للعجب! كان هناك شركات النقل بالشاحنات.
and brick-and-mortar and marketing firms, and CD jewel case manufacturers,
وشركات التجارة التقليدية وشركات التسويق وشركات الاسطوانات المدمجة،
all devoted to these two problems.
كل هذا خصص لتلك المشكلتين.
And then we all know what happened.
وبعد ذلك، كلنا يعرف ما حدث
10 years ago, the internet matures
منذ عشر أعوام، تطورت الإنترنت
and we get Spotify and Facebook and YouTube
وحصلنا على سبوتي فاي وفيسبوك ويوتيوب
and iTunes and Google search,
و اي تونز و جوجل.
and a hundred years of infrastructure
مائة عام من البنية التحتية
and supply chains and distribution systems
وسلاسل الإمدادات وأنظمة التوزيع
and monetization schemes
وسك العملات
are completely bypassed --
تم التغاضي عنها بالكامل...
in a decade.
في عقد من الزمان.
After 100 years of designing these things,
بعد مائة عام من تصميم هذه الأشياء،
it's no wonder that it's just totally broken for creative people right now.
ولاعجب أن النظام توقف للمبدعين في الوقت الحالي.
It's no wonder that the monetization part of the chain doesn't work
ولا عجب أن جزء تحقيق الدخل من السلسلة لا يعمل
given this new context.
ليعطينا هذا السياق الجديد.
But what gets me super excited to be a creator right now,
ولكن ما يجعلني متحمسا كثيرا كشخص مبتكر في الوقت الحالي،
to be alive today and be a creative person right now,
وأعيش في الوقت الحالي وكوني شخص مبدع،
is realizing that we're only 10 years into figuring out this new machine --
هو معرفة أننا في أول عشر سنوات من اكتشاف هذه الآلية الجديدة.
to figuring out the next 100 years of infrastructure for our creators.
واكتشاف المائة عاما القادمة من البنية الأساسية للمبدعين.
And you can tell we're only 10 years in.
وبإمكانك القول أننا في أول عشر أعوام منها.
There's a lot of trial and error, some really good ideas forming,
يوجد الكثير من المحاولة والخطأ وأفكار جيدة تتبلور.
a lot of experimentation.
والكثير من التجارب.
We're figuring out what works and what doesn't.
نحن نكتشف ما ينفع وما لا ينفع.
Like Twitch streamers. Who's heard of Twitch?
مثل تويتش استريمرز هل سمع أحدكم عن تويتش؟
Twitch streamers are making three to five thousand bucks a month
يكسب تويتش استريمرز ما بين ثلاثة إلى خمسة ألف دولار شهرياً
streaming gaming content.
من بث محتوي الألعاب.
The big ones are making over 100,000 dollars a year.
ودخل المواقع الأكبر أكثر من 100,000دولار سنوياً.
There's a site called YouNow,
هناك موقع يوناو،
it's an app.
عبارة عن تطبيق.
It allows musicians and vloggers to get paid in digital goods from fans.
يسمح للموسيقيين ومدوني الفيديو بالحصول على المال من السلع الرقمية من المعجبين.
So, I'm also working on the problem.
كذلك، فأنا أعمل على حل المشكلة أيضاً.
Four years ago I started a company called Patreon
منذ أربعة أعوام أنشئت شركة الباتريون
with a friend of mine.
مع صديق لي.
We're 80 people now working on this problem.
ونحن 80 شخصاً الآن يعملون على حل لهذه المشكلة.
It's basically a membership platform
إنها عبارة عن منصة عضوية
that makes it really easy for creators to get paid --
تجعل من السهل جدا للمبدعين تقاضى المال...
every month from their fans to earn a living.
شهرياً من المعجبين لكسب معيشتهم.
For a creator, it's like having a salary for being a creative person.
وبالنسبه للمبدعين فهو مثل الحصول على راتب لكونه شخص مبتكر.
And this is one of our creators.
وهؤلاء بعض من مبدعينا.
They're called "Kinda Funny."
يدعون "كيندا فاني".
They have about 220,000 subscribers on YouTube.
لديهم أكثر من 220 الف متابع على اليوتيوب.
And when they upload a video,
وعندما يحملون فيديو،
it gets somewhere around 15,000 views to 100,000 views.
فعدد مشاهداته تصل ما بين 15,000 إلى 100,000 مشاهدة.
I want you to check yourselves right now.
أريدكم أن تراجعوا أنفسكم الآن.
I think when we hear numbers like that, when we hear "15,000 views,"
أعتقد أنه عندما نسمع رقم مثل ذلك، عندما نسمع "15,000 مشاهدة،"
and we see content like this,
ونرى محتوى مثل هذا.
we just snap categorize it as being not as legitimate
فإننا نتسرع فى الحكم عليه بانه ليس قانونياً مثله
as a morning show that you'd hear on the radio
مثل "مورننج شو" الذي تسمعه علي الراديو
or a talk show that you'd see on NBC or something
أو البرامج الحواري الذي تشاهده على ان بي سي
But when "Kinda Funny" launched on Patreon,
ولكن عندما اُذيع كيندا فاني على باتريون،
within a few weeks, they were making 31,000 dollars per month
في خلال أسابيع فقط، صاروا يجنون 31,000 دولاراً شهرياً
for this show.
لهذا البرنامج.
It took off so fast that they decided to expand their programming
لقد حققوا نجاحاً سريعاً ولذلك قرروا زيادة برامجهم
and add new shows,
وإضافة عروض جديدة،
and now they launched a second Patreon page --
والآن أطلقوا صفحة باتريون أخرى--
they're making an additional 21,000 dollars per month.
إنهم يحصلون على 21,000 دولارا إضافيه شهرياً.
And they're scaling what's essentially becoming a media company,
ويرتقون إلى شركة إعلامية،
financing the whole thing through membership.
وقد تم تمويل كل ذلك من خلال العضوية.
OK, here's another example.
حسنا، هذا مثال آخر.
This is Derek Bodner,
هذا هو ديرك بودنر،
a sports journalist who used to write for Philadelphia Magazine
صحافي رياضي كان يكتب في مجلة فيلادلفيا
until a few months ago when the magazine cut out all sports coverage.
ولكن منذ بضعة أشهر ألغت المجلة كل التغطية الرياضية.
Now he writes articles and publishes them on his own website --
والآن يكتب المقالات وينشرها على موقعه الخاص...
he's still covering sports, but for himself.
لا يزال يغطي أخبار الرياضة ولكن لصالح نفسه.
And he's making 4,800 bucks a month from 1,700 patrons,
ويجني 4,800 دولاراً شهريا من 1,700 راع،
financing it through membership.
يمول ذلك من خلال العضوية.
This is Crash Course --
وهذا كراش كورس...
free educational content for the world.
محتوى تعليمي مجاني للعالم أجمع.
This show is actually on the PBS digital network --
وهذا البرنامج موجود بالقعل علي شبكة بي بي أس...
29,000 dollars per month.
يجني 29,000 دولار شهرياً.
This is a duo sailing around the world,
وهذا "ديو سيلنج اروند ذا ورلد"،
getting paid every month for documenting their travels
يتقاضون أجراً شهرياً مقابل توثيقهم لرحلاتهم
from 1,400 patrons.
من 14,000 راعي.
This is a podcast, "Chapo Trap House", making --
وهذه المدونه الصوتية، "تشوب تراب هاوس،" تجني...
actually, since I screenshotted this,
في الحقيقة، منذ التقطت هذه اللقطة،
they're making an additional 2,000 dollars per month,
فقد جنوا 2,000 دولاراً شهرياً،
so they're now making 56,000 dollars per month for their podcast.
والآن يجنون 56,000 دولاراً شهرياً من خلال مدونتهم الصوتية.
And Patreon's not the only one working on the problem.
ليس باتريون فقط من يعملون على حل المشكلة.
Even Google's starting to work on this.
حتى جوجل بدأ بالعمل على حل هذه المشكلة.
A couple years ago, they launched Fan Funding;
منذ بضع سنين، طرحوا "التمويل من المعجبين"،
more recently, they launched Super Chat
ومؤخراً اطلقوا "سوبر شات"
as a way for creators to monetize live streaming.
كطريقة للمبدعين يجنون فيها المال من البث الحي.
Newspapers are starting to experiment with membership.
وبدأت الصحف في التجريب مع العضوية.
New York Times has a membership program;
فلدى نيويورك تايمز برنامج عضوية:
The Guardian has over 200,000 paying subscribers
ولدى الجارديان اكثر من 200,000 مشتركين دفع
to its membership program.
لبرنامج عضويتهم.
There's this bubbling soup of ideas and experiments
وهناك الكثير من الافكار والتجارب
and progress right now,
والتقدم في الوقت الحالي،
and it's pointing in the direction of getting creators paid.
وكلها تهدف إلى تمكين المبدعين من الحصول على المال.
And it's working.
وهذا يجدي نفعاً.
It's not, like, perfect yet,
إنه ليس مثالياً بعد،
but it's really working.
ولكنه يجدي نفعاً.
So, Patreon has over 50,000 creators on the platform making salaries --
فالباتريون لديها اكثر من 50,000 مبدع يحصلون على رواتب...
getting paid every month for putting art online,
يتقاضون شهرياً لوضعهم الفن على الانترنت.
for being a creative person.
ولكونهم أشخاصا مبدعين،
The next hundred years of infrastructure is on the way
المائة عاماً القادمة من البنية الأساسية آتية في الطريق
and it's going to be different this time because of this --
وستكون مختلفة هذه المرة بسبب...
because of the direct connection between the person who makes the thing
بسبب الصلة المباشرة بين الشخص المنتج لهذه الأشياء
and the person who likes the thing.
والشخص المحب لهذه الاشياء.
About seven or eight years ago,
منذ سبع أو ثماني سنوات مضت،
I went to a cocktail party.
ذهبت إلى حفل كوكتيل.
This is when the band had hit our first machine,
وذلك كان أول مرة تعزف فرقنتا،
so things were really cranking.
والأمور كانت تتقدم.
We had just made about 400,000 dollars in one year
فقد جنينا 400,000 دولاراً في عام واحد.
through iTunes sales and brand deals and stuff like that.
من مبيعات اي تونز وصفقات العلامات التجارية وما إلى ذلك.
And this guy comes up to me and says,
فيأتي هذا الشخص ويقول لي،
"Hey, Jack, what do you do?"
"مرحبا جاك، ماذا تعمل؟"
I said, "I'm a musician."
قلت: "أنا موسيقار."
And he just sobered up immediately,
فأفاق في الحال،
and he stuck out his hand,
وفرد يديه،
put a hand on my shoulder,
ووضعهما على كتفي،
and in a real earnest, very nice voice he was like,
وبصوت جاد صريح قال:
"I hope you make it someday."
"أتمنى أن تنجح في يوم من الأيام."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And ...
و...
I have so many moments like that logged in my memory.
لدي الكثير مثل تلك اللحظات قابعة في ذاكرتي.
I just cringe thinking of that.
أحرج من التفكير فيها.
It's so embarrassing to just not feel valued as a creative person.
إنه لأمر محرج أن تشعر بعدم التقدير كشخص مبدع.
But as a species,
بل كجماعة،
we are leaving that cocktail party behind.
وضعنا حفل الكوكتيل خلفنا.
We're leaving that culture,
ونسينا هذه الثقافة،
we're out of there.
وخرجنا من هناك.
We're going to get so good at paying creators,
سنطور الطريقه ليتمكن المبدعين من جني المال،
within 10 years,
في خلال 10 سنوات،
kids graduating high school and college are going to think of being a creator
والأطفال خريجي المدرسة الثانوية والجامعة، سيفكرون في أن يصبحوا أشخاص مبدعين
as just being an option --
كخيار لهم...
I could be a doctor, I could be a lawyer,
يمكني أن اكون طبيب أو محامي،
I could be a podcaster, I could have a web comic.
أن أكون صاحب مدونة صوتية، أو يكون لي موقع فكاهي.
It's just going to be something you can do.
سيصبح شيء بإمكانك فعله.
We're figuring it out.
ونحن سنكتشف ذلك.
It's going to be a viable and sustainable and respected profession.
ستصبح وظيفة متاحة ودائمة ومحترمة.
Creators are going to come out the other end of this weird 100 years,
وسيصل المبدعون إلى نهاية هذه المئة عام العجيبة،
this century-long journey,
ورحلة هذا القرن الطويلة،
with an awesome new machine.
سيخرجون بآلية جديدة مذهلة.
And they're going to be paid, and they're going to be valued.
وسيجنون المال وسيقدرهم الناس.
Thanks, everybody.
شكرا جميعا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
I think it went pretty well.
أعتقد ان الأمر سار على ما يرام.
I want artists who saw that to not give up --
أريد من كل الفنانين الذين شاهدوا هذا، ألا يستسلموا...
to know that we're getting there.
ويعلموا أننا سنصل لتلك المرحلة.
It's not there yet,
لم نصل بعد،
but in a couple years,
ولكن في عدة أعوام،
there will be so many systems and tools for them
سيوجد الكثير من الأنظمة والأدوات مخصصة لهم
to just make a living online,
لكي يكسبوا معيشتهم من خلال الإنترنت،
and if they've got a podcast that's starting to take off,
وإذا كان لديهم مدونة صوتية في طور الانطلاق،
but they're not able to make money on it yet,
ولكنهم غير قادرين على جني المال حتى الآن،
that's happening
ذلك سيتحقق
and they're going to be paid.
وسيجنون المال.
It's happening.
إنه يتحقق.